Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nguyen-ngoc-thach (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

IT Business Analysis
Business Analysis Planning &
Monitoring
SQL

Nguyen Ngoc Thach

Business Analyst and Project Management Vietnam

Summary

After completing 4 years of university and amassing some work experience, I have found a passion in consulting and analyzing solutions to bring the best value to clients and the company.

With a vibrant, open-minded personality, able to communicate and team-work, I want to accumulate more experience to become a professional solution consultant for business and learn many new experience from projects and challenges

Experience

Buymed
Business Analyst
August 2023 - Present (1 year 8 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Buymed is Vietnam's and Southeast Asia's top health-tech company. Company's vision is improving healthcare quality and access for practitioners, patients, and all other stakeholders (pharmaceutical producers, distributors, logistics providers, and pharmacists) in between by using transformational technology.

- As the Business Analyst for Buymed's Business Intelligence (BI) team, I have played a crucial role in enhancing our analytics platform and managing a team of 7 members.
- Led the implementation of BI projects, from receiving requests and defining requirements to wireframing and mockup creation for report development.
- Collaborated closely with internal stakeholders to understand and communicate the vision for the analytics platform, ensuring alignment with strategic organizational goals.
- Transformed co-worker requirements into clear user stories and acceptance criteria, providing comprehensive guidance for the development team.
- Prioritized and managed the product backlog, refining priorities based on user feedback, changing business dynamics, and emerging analytical trends.

- Advocated for user-centric design principles, collaborating with UX/UI designers to ensure an intuitive and efficient user experience.
- Collaborated with internal communication teams to craft engaging user communications, training materials, and resources.
- Participated in sprint reviews and retrospectives to continually enhance the platform's capabilities and user experience.

CMC Saigon Technology & Solution (CMC TSSG)
Database Administrator
April 2022 - July 2023 (1 year 4 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

CMC TSSG aims to occupy the top position in Digital Transformation solutions for government, organization and business, maintain 100% market share in the Financial – Banking sector as well as confirm the lead role in providing Data Services, IT Managed Services, Information Security and Cloud Computing.

- Responsible for building the database queries and optimize them to achieve to best performance in the big database;
- Ensure the new/existing queries to return the correct data in the shorted time;
- Administer database systems, ensuring stability and fine-tuning Oracle database;
- Resolve incidents and participate in problem resolutions;
- Uses business intelligence data and tools to identify and create reports to risk manager;
- Compiling data regarding reported issues and offering remedies that improve the operation of processes and systems.

Key achievement:

• Improved performance 30 queries cost 4 to 6 times lower than original cost, query time is 2 to 3 times faster than original query time.

Green Agri Technology
Project Owner
June 2021 - March 2022 (10 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Green Agri Technology has built and deployed technology solutions to businesses, cooperatives, cooperative groups, farmers... in order to digitize jobs in the process of production, harvesting, purchasing and processing. processing and consuming products through 2 technology platforms, Green Check and Green Agri.

- Coordinate internal resources and third parties/vendors for the flawless execution of projects;
- Ensure that all projects are delivered on-time, within scope and within budget;
- Developing project scopes and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility;
- Ensure resource availability and allocation;
- Develop a detailed project plan to track progress;
- Measure project performance using appropriate systems, tools and techniques;
- Report and escalate to management as needed;
- Manage the relationship with the client and all stakeholders;
- Perform risk management to minimize project risks;
- Establish and maintain relationships with third parties/vendors;
- Create and maintain comprehensive project documentation.

Key achievement:

- Successfully delivered two completed products, Green Agri and Green Check, meeting the established project goals and client expectations.
- Ensured the fulfillment of requirements from relevant stakeholders, addressing their needs and incorporating feedback into the project's development.
- Ensured smooth operations from the backend to the frontend, focusing on both technical functionality and user interface/user experience (UI/UX) design.

Education

University Of Economics Ho Chi Minh City
College Degree, Business Information Technology · (September 2017 - September 2021)